Faiza Mahmoud

Software Developer Denver, CO

faiza_mahmoud@icloud.com · LinkedIn · GitHub

As a Software Developer with a diverse background in math, sales operations, and sales compensation, I am confident that my unique skill set and strong work ethic make me a valuable asset to the Moody's corporations' development team. I am always striving to learn and improve, and I am comfortable giving and receiving constructive feedback. My ability to work with data and make informed decisions, as well as my experience collaborating with cross-functional teams, make me well-suited for this role. I am also highly adaptable and able to quickly learn and utilize new technologies.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript ES6, Python, HTML5/CSS3

Database - PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Libraries - jQuery, Bcrypt, Passport, Bootstrap, Axios, EJS

Frameworks - React, Node.js, Express, Django

Other - RESTful Routing, Git, JSON, Heroku, Netlify, Passport JSON Web Token(JWT)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Lean On Me | GitHub | Live

12/2022

Animal Shelter volunteer locator

- Joined the Winter Hackathon where I got the opportunity to collaborate with UX/UI designers and software developers in a 3-day sprint
- Designed the layout in Figma, code the app in React to precise speciation's, and pitch the app to a panel of judges in the industry
- Managed the main branch of GitHub and helped team members with troubleshooting and debugging

Technologies: React, Bootstrap, Axios, Netlify

Sabah | GitHub | Live

10/2022

Perfume Ecommerce website

- Created a full stack Ecommerce website using MERN stack so users can create a profile, purchase/save perfumes in favorites while also getting educated on the notes that comprise that perfume
- Implemented Passport strategy for authorization JSON Web Token and authentication for user registration and login

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB/Mongoose, REST API, HTML, Bootstrap/CSS, Heroku

TravelHub | GitHub | Live

09/2022

Blog-style forum related to travel

- Collaborated with developers to implement RESTFUL APIs in Express.js so that users can create posts, comments and interact on posts created by other users
- Implemented express-session for authorization

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, express-session, MongoDB, Mongoose, REST API, HTML, EJS, Heroku

BlackJackStacks | GitHub | Live

08/2022

Classic game of Blackjack

• Designed and implemented a single player & dealer game using object-oriented programming (Inheritance and encapsulation) and DOM manipulation

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, GitHub Pages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Compensation Analyst II | ServiceSource inc. | Denver, CO

07/2018 - 07/2020

- Spearheaded the commission calculations process monthly, across nine sales centers globally to drive sales performance aligned with the goals at Service Source.
- Provided sales executives a translated and contextualized summary and analysis based on sales compensation performance against targets, which provided clarity on outliers and anomalies.
- Collaborated with full teams on each of the following departments: Sales Operations, Finance, and HR to identify and implement process improvements by delivering new Sales Force quota structure & validation which added more efficient layer of auditing proficiency

Sr. Operations Analyst | ServiceSource, | Denver, CO

05/2016 - 07/2018

- Collaborated with Hitachi Vantara renewals team to develop & sell multi-million-dollar enterprise hardware/software solutions to clients, which led to maintain the standard metric of renewal rates of at least 80%.
- As a subject-matter expert, I coached & trained analysts by providing audits of their sales quotes and led sales process changes/improvements assisting in faster turnaround times in the sales cycle.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

07/2022 - 10/2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Metropolitan State University of Denver | Denver, CO

05/2016

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics, Economics